# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I'm going to share a homestyle dish with you.
# 蔬菜煎饼
Vegetable Pancake
# 首先我们准备1小节青瓜切成薄片
First let's prepare 1 small piece of cucumber cut into thin slices.
# 准备1颗香菇切成薄片备用
Prepare 1 mushroom, thinly sliced
# 准备大红椒1个去掉辣椒籽之后切成细丝备用
Prepare 1 red bell pepper by removing the seeds and cutting it into strips.
# 准备西红柿1个直接切成薄片备用
Prepare 1 tomato, cut into thin slices.
# 准备适量的洋葱切成小粒备用
Chop a bit onion into fine dice for later use.
# 准备鸡蛋4个打入盆中
Add 4 eggs in a bowl.
# 盆中加入面粉1小把
Add 1 small handful of flour to the bowl
# 加入玉米淀粉1小把
Add 1 small handful of cornstarch
# 加入土豆淀粉1小把
Add 1 small handful of potato starch
# 加入食用盐1小勺搅拌均匀备用
Add 1 small spoon of table salt and mix well.
# 中途加入适量的熟芝麻拌匀
Add some cooked sesame seeds and mix well.
# 最后加入少许的花生油拌匀
Finally, add some peanut oil and mix well.
# 加花生油的目的是增香
The purpose of adding peanut oil is to add flavor.
# 然后再陆续加入洋葱 青瓜 香菇和红椒丝拌匀
Then add the onions, cucumbers, mushrooms and red peppers and mix well.
# 同学们除了西红柿之外都可以切成颗粒
You can dice everything except the tomato.
# 且西红柿应该在煎制的中途加入
And the tomatoes should be added halfway through frying.
# 这样可以防止出水稀释面浆
This will prevent tomato juice from diluting the batter.
# 最后再准备熟透的香蕉1根切成薄片备用
Finally, prepare 1 ripened banana, thinly sliced.
# 香蕉容易氧化变黑所以安排在最后处理
Bananas are prone to oxidation and blackening, so cut it right before cooking.
# 下一步开始制作
Start cooking next.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First, heat up the wok.
# 锅烧热之后将蔬菜捞出放入锅底摆成圆形
When the wok is hot, put the vegetables to the wok.
# 然后将切好的西红柿均匀地围在边上
Then evenly place the tomato slices around the edge.
# 摆放整齐之后将剩余的面糊从边上淋下
Once neatly arranged, drizzle the remaining batter down the side.
# 最后加入切好的香蕉片转微小火煎10分钟左右
Add the sliced banana and fry on low heat for about 10 minutes.
# 面糊越薄煎制的时间则越短
The thinner the batter, the shorter the frying time.
# 一般来说家庭的平底锅更加适合此菜
Flat bottom non-sticking pans are generally better for this dish.
# 面饼成型之后开始摇动铁锅
Once the shape is fixed, start shaking the wok.
# 然后再翻过来煎另外一面
Then you flip it over and fry the other side.
# 同学们煎制的时候必须小火慢煎
You should cook it on low heat.
# 将原材料充分煎熟
Brown the ingredients thoroughly
# 翻面之后可以用锅铲轻轻按压 使其均匀受热
After you flip it over, you can press it with a spatula to heat it evenly.
# 10分钟之后煎熟即可出锅装盘
After 10 minutes, it's ready to serve.
# 一道非常美味的蔬菜煎饼就制作完成
A very tasty vegetable pancake is ready.
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一
First,
# 蔬菜可以根据各自的口味添加
Different vegetables can be added according to your own taste.
# 含水量大的蔬菜不能直接切粒
Vegetables with high water content should not be diced directly.
# 防止水份析出
Prevents the juice going into the batter.
# 第二
Second,
# 总的来说平底锅更适合新手操作
Overall flat-bottomed pans are better for beginners
# 且全程都需要开小火煎制
And it needs to be cooked on low heat all the way through.
# 第三
Third,
# 煎饼出锅之后也可以切成小片方便食用
The pancakes can also be cut into small slices for easy eating once they are out of the pan.
# 蔬菜煎饼的技术总结完毕
That's all the technique summary for vegetable pancake.